Charles Clement Gomes

Address: 2623 Ascot Way, Union City, CA 94587 Cell No: 669-800-9178 Email:charles2588@gmail.com

Blogs:- <u>Medium</u> Open Source:- <u>Github</u> Community Efforts:- <u>Stackoverflow.com</u>

I am a Senior Software Engineer with experience working as Full stack engineer with excellent problem solving, debugging skills, and have worked with high revenue enterprise customers to debug issues, develop solutions and deliver code fixes.

Work Experience

Software Engineer at Meta/Facebook Inc.

(Aug 2021 – Present)

- Worked on Meta's <u>Workplace</u> product to implement various integration features such as working on Work Directory, SSO authentication, <u>SCIM API</u>, <u>Graph APIs</u>.
- Worked on developing and fixing high customer-impacting core features like messenger, news feed, video, video analytics.
- Worked on fixing many critical customer email, sms and jewel notification issues in the Workplace Product to reduce customer's impact.
- Designed and implemented a scalable React based <u>meta status page/workplace</u> web app deployed in AWS to support and provide an outage-based notification system for Facebook developers and enterprise users using AWS lambda, S3, RDS, and Terraform.
- Worked on internal and external tooling's frontend and backend codebase in React and Hack/PHP to implement user data privacy features. Worked on writing integration, Jest end to end and unit tests.
- Worked on <u>Facebook Developer Community Forum</u> to implement upvote and downvote features as well implemented new notifications to inform users on digest and improve user experience.
- Implemented Privacy specific features to ensure user's data is purged as per privacy controls.

Software Engineer at IBM Inc. - Lead Cloud Engineer

(Feb 2018 – July 2021)

- Lead Advance Customer Cloud Team for Revenue driving Premium Customers supporting <u>Watson AI / Machine Learning Services</u> and taking ownership of critical production issues from diagnosis, root cause analysis to delivering fix. Work with cross-functional teams to build and fix REST APIs for <u>watson machine learning</u> and <u>watson assistant</u>.
- Designed and Developed scalable end to end productivity solution(using Python, Github API,slack) in order to manage service
 escalations and auto follow up with multiple teams and multiple products which improved support engineers productivity.
 Designed and Developed Dashboard to consolidate development engagements(using Python, Cognos Dashboard)
- Handle the machine learning modeling, training, deployment and monitoring issues and diagnose python, R as well as support cloud service sdks and api issues(http authentication,latency,downstream failures).
- Manage and handle Hadoop, Hive, Spark clusters for customers, dealing with provisioning, scaling, production job issues.
- Write technical documents, programming notebooks, knowledge articles, and respond to product questions on social media.

Software Engineer at IBM Inc.

(July 2012 - Jan 2018)

- Managed and Handled IBM Cloud Spark service by handling operational alerts and working on customer issues including
 provisioning of clusters to running the jobs in production and diagnosing the critical production jobs.
- Published medium articles in order to deflect customer issues and make the resolution faster.
- Handled customer cloud onboarding issues and fixed product specific defects using Linux, Cloud PaaS, Hadoop, and Spark, Python, Scala, R.
- Developed automated test scripts using python and shell script and handled deployments on jenkins.
- Diagnosed customer's database related issues of connectivity, sql scripts, migration, administration and development.
- Created, maintained test cases and ran manual tests for IBM Data Studio and Infosphere Data Architect.

Web Developer at OneVasai LTD.

(July 2009 - Feb 2010)

Designed, Developed and Maintained website for local magazine using html,css and javascript.

Education

MS in Computer Science

New York Institute of Technology, NYC, NY, USA

BS in Computer Engineering

St. Francis Institute of Technology, Mumbai, India

July 2009

Skills

Primary Python, HTML5, Javascript, CSS3, PHP/Hack, GraphQL, ReactJS,
Secondary Java, R, Scala, SQL, Shell, Node.js, AngularJS, Android, Kubernetes, IAM, AWS, Azure
Tools Docker, Git, Jupyter Notebook, Hadoop, Spark, Machine Learning, IBM Cloud, Watson Studio, Cognos, Mongodb

<u>Certifications</u>: <u>Big Data Spark Foundations</u>, <u>Data Science Professional Certificate</u>, <u>Advanced Machine Learning and Signal Processing</u>, <u>Data Analysis with Python</u>, <u>Spark Technical Concepts</u>, <u>Big Data Spark Foundation</u>

Personal Projects: Play Store Apps, aitool.fyi